Guide to the Camp Kinderland Records TAM.439
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IX: Photographic and Audiovisual Materials, 1924-2010
  - Glass Plate Negatives
    - Dining room workers, Aug 28, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Directors Meeting, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Erecting the Kinderland sign on the main entrance, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Erecting the Kinderland sign on the main entrance, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Erecting the Kinderland sign on the main entrance, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Exercising, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Exercising, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Exercising, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Exercising, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Exercising, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Exercising, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Female campers with anti-war posters, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Fifth Group, 1935 (Box 27)
    - First Class, Aug 17, 1935 (Box 27)
    - First Group, Jul 27, 1935 (Box 29)
    - First Group, Jul 27, 1935 (Box 29)
    - First National Teachers' Conference, Sep 1935 (Box 28)
    - First National Teachers' Conference, Sep 1935 (Box 28)
    - First National Teachers' Conference, Sep 1935 (Box 30)
    - Fourth Group, Aug 4, 1935 (Box 27)
    - French United Front, Anti-war Congress, 1935 (Box 27)
    - French United Front, Anti-war Congress, 1935 (Box 28)
    - French United Front, Anti-war Congress, 1935 (Box 28)
    - French United Front, Anti-war Congress, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Friday morning, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Garden work, Bunk 19, 1935 (Box 29)
    - Girl in front of children's dining room, 1930s (Box 29)
    - Group 1. Joseph Cutler banner., Aug 31, 1935 (Box 29)
    - Group 10, Bunk 5 (gardening group), Aug 25, 1935 (Box 29)
    - Group 2, Jul 17, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Group 2, Jul 17, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Group 2, Jul 17, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Group 2, Bunk 33-34, Aug 20, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Group 3, Bunk 6, 8, 9, 19, 21, 23, Jul 12, 1935 (Box 29)
    - Group 3, Bunks 6, 8, 9, 19, 21, 23, Jul 12, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Group 4, Jul 14, 1936 (Box 28)
    - Group 5, Jul 17, 1935 (Box 29)
    - Group 5, Bunks 10, 11, 12, Jul 15, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Group 8, Bunk 3 (girls doing arts and crafts), Aug 18, 1935 (Box 29)
    - Group in front of entrance, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Group in front of entrance, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Group in front of Lenin Monument, Sep 2, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Group of boys with a "Blacks and Whites United" Sign, 1930s (Box 27)
    - Group portrait, 1930s (Box 29)
    - Group Portrait, Aug 25, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Group Portrait, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Group Portrait, Aug 4, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Group Portrait, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Group Portrait, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 20, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Group Portrait, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Group Portrait, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 26, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 25, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Group Portrait, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Group Portrait, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Sep 2, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 13, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 24, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 24, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 20, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 24, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 12, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 24, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Aug 16, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 16, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 15, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 26, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Aug 3, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 12, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 16, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, Jul 20, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Group Portrait with Hammer and Sickle, 1935 (Box 27)
    - In front of campfire, 1930s (Box 28)
    - In the bushes near the Infirmary, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Kindergarden, Aug 13, 1935 (Box 29)
    - Kindergarden, Aug 3, 1935 (Box 29)
    - Kinderland Choir, Aug 4, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Kinderland Choir, Aug 24, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Kinderland Choir, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Kinderland Choir, Jul 27, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Kinderland Choir, Jul 13, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Kinderland Choir, Aug 10, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Kinderland Choir, undated (Box 27)
    - Kinderland Choir, Aug 24, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Kinderland Choir, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Kinderland entrance, 1930s (Box 29)
    - Kinderland office, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Laundry Room, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Lesson with Gina Medem, Jul 25, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Lesson with Gina Medem, Jul 25, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Library, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Listening to lecture, Aug 31, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Literary corner, Jul 13, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Literature Booth, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Lowlies, 1935 (Box 29)
    - LSNR Meeting, Aug 17, 1935 (Box 27)
    - LSNR Meeting, Aug 17, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Man and Girl, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Man and Woman, 1930s-1940s (Box 29)
    - Man and Woman, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Man and Woman, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Man and Woman, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Man and Woman, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Man and Woman, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Man and Woman, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Man using a water fountain, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Medal Forum, Aug 13, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Morning Salute, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Morning Salute, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Morning Salute, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Morning Salute, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Morning Salute, Jul 5, 1936 (Box 28)
    - Morning Salute, Jul 5, 1936 (Box 28)
    - Morning Salute, Jul 5, 1936 (Box 28)
    - Morning Salute, Jul 5, 1936 (Box 28)
    - Morning Salute, Jul 5, 1936 (Box 28)
    - Morning Salute, Jul 5, 1936 (Box 30)
    - Mural, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Office Staff, 1935 (Box 29)
    - Office Staff, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Office Staff, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Open Forum, Aug 13, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Open Forum, Aug 7, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Open Forum, Aug 14, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Open Forum, Aug 14, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Parents by the entrance, Aug 25, 1935 (Box 29)
    - Partially exposed or damaged negative, circa 1935 (Box 27)
    - Primary School, Aug 15, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Primary School, Aug 15, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Red Square Building, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Registration in Camp Kinderland office, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Robert Minor at Camp Kinderland, Aug 10, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Robert Minor at Camp Kinderland, Aug 10, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Second American Youth Congress, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Second Group, 1935 (Box 29)
    - Shot of a group of school children at Camp Kinderland, Aug 7, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Solo Portrait, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Study Group, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Study Group, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Study Group, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Study Group, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Study Group, Jul 20, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Study Group, Aug 12, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Study Group, Jul 15, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Study Group, Aug 28, 1935 (Box 30)
    - Study Group, Jul 31, 1935 (Box 27)
    - Suitcases, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Teaching Class, Aug 29, 1935 (Box 28)
    - The unveiling of the Lenin monument, Aug 25, 1935 (Box 28)
    - The unveiling of the Lenin monument, Aug 25, 1935 (Box 28)
    - The unveiling of the Lenin monument, Aug 25, 1935 (Box 28)
    - The unveiling of the Lenin monument, Aug 25, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Three Boys Outside, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 29)
    - Three Women, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Two Men, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Two Men, 1930s (Box 28)
    - Two Women, 1930s (Box 30)
    - Waterfront, 1935 (Box 28)
    - Woman, 1930s (Box 27)
  - 57 negatives of Camp Kinderland, mostly group portraits and images from events, 1938-1943 (Box 29)
  - Arts and Crafts, 1996; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Bunk Opening Ceremony and New Dining Hall Frame (Freiheit), undated; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Bus Departures, 1982; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Camp Life, circa 1940-1949; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Camp Life (Oversize Reproductions), circa 1940-1949; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Camp Life (Oversize Reproductions), circa 1930-1949; 2 folders (Box 26)
  - Chankukah Party and Chaike Klebansky, 1991; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Demonstrations, 1956-1957, 1993; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Events, circa 1970-1979, 1991, 1997-2001; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Group Shots, 2004, 2009-2010; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Group Shot (Oversize), 2004 (Box 10)
  - Itzkowitz, Ben (Camp Photographer), undated; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Itzkowitz, Ben (Oversize), undated; 1 folder (Box 26)
  - Kinderland-Lakeland Entrance, undated; 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Murals, 1998-2005; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Murals/Other Art (Oversize), circa 1959, 1998-2005; 1 folder (Box 10)
  - "Peace" Mural, undated; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Publicity, circa 1939-1952 (Box 10)
  - 75th Anniversary Reunion Posters, 1 folder (Box 10)
  - Yackle 60th Anniversary Reunion, September 19-21, 2003; 1 folder (Box 9)
  - Banners with Russian Writing; Button; "Soviet Union Welcomes You!" Poster, undated (Box 11)
  - 75th Anniversary Dinner Tickets (Box 11)
  - Group Portrait (Oversize), 2008 (Box 11)
  - Oral History Interviews with Former Campers; Videocassettes, Index, and Questions, 2005 (Box 12)
  - Oral History Interviews and Assorted Audio and Audiovisual Materials; 18 Videocassettes, 10 Audiocassettes, Reels, and 5 CDs, 1960-2004 (Box 13)
  - Camp Activities and Plays; Videocassettes, DVDs, and Reels, circa 1995-2002 (Box 14)
  - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1924-1936 (Box 15)
  - Camp Activities and Group Shots, circa 1940-1947 (Box 16)
  - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1948-1953 (Box 17)
  - Camp Activities and Group Shots, circa 1960-1969 (Box 18)
  - Camp Activities and Group Shots, 1970-1983 (Box 19)
  - Senior Camper Photograph Albums, circa 1989-2000 (Box 20)
  - Camp Activities and Group Shots, circa 1991-2000 (Box 21)
  - Slides, circa 1930-1949 (Box 22)
  - Slides, circa 1960-1969 (Box 22)
  - Slides, 1983-1984 (Box 22)
  - Slides, circa 1940-1949 (Box 23)
  - Slides, circa 1960-1969 (Box 23)
  - Slides, circa 1980-1989 (Box 24)
  - Seal Press, 1954 (Box 25)
  - 16mm Reels (Includes Yiddish Lessons), undated (Box 25)
- Series XI: Archived Website, Apr 1, 2012-ongoing
  Camp Kinderland was founded on Sylvan Lake in Hopewell Junction, NY in 1923 by members of the Workmen's Circle who worked in the organization's New York City schools. The camp's founders sought to create a summer youth camp that would not only provide a recreational escape for the children of working people from the tenements of New York City, but also one whose culture would encourage and foster a commitment to socially progressive activism and the embracing of a rich Jewish secular tradition. The website contains news and event listings, camper and parent resources, and information about renting their facilities.